This is an improv icebreaker called pass the clap.
Okay, insert your naughty joke here.
Alright, it's pass the clap.
It's simple, it's classic.
It's so portable.
You can use it any time.
I learned it in one of my first improv classes and fifteen years later I am still doing it today.
Pass the clap.
So, this just helps people get connected and really in the moment with each other, and how it works is you're going to get a group in a circle.
The classic improv formation.
And if I was to start I'm going to make eye contact with someone in the circle and I'm going to clap at them.
Thus, passing the clap.
Once they get it, they're going to make eye contact with someone and they're going to clap at them.
And this clap is going to be whizzing around the circle.
As with all improv games, one of the things we want to work on is pacing.
The faster you go, the more challenging and exciting it will be.
That's where the risk is that's where the fun is.
So, hopefully it's going really fast.
Passing back and forth.
Zoom zoom zoom around the circle.
If that gets a little boring then what you can do is you can start moving around the room and clapping at people as people are moving around and that can give a whole other kind of movement dynamic.
The focus is for this game, is pacing and eye contact.
Making sure you really connect with people and deliver the clap right to them.
So, that is a classic improv warm up called pass the clap.